Upton Sinclair Miscellaneous Materials VI: Book Reviews by Sinclair, 1904-1954 PS3537.I85 (InU-Li-VAE1863)
Lilly Library
Upton Sinclair Miscellaneous Materials VI: Book Reviews by Sinclair
1904-1954
1957
Lilly Library
PS3537.I85 (InU-Li-VAE1863)
17 Items
This collection consists of book reviews written by Upton Sinclair and published in various magazines, newspapers, and journals.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Biographical Note
Upton Sinclair, 1878-1968, author, is best-known for his classic muck-raking novel The Jungle, which exposed labor and sanitary conditions in the U.S. meatpacking industry.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged chronologically by publication date.
Scope and Content Note
This collection consists of book reviews written by Upton Sinclair and published in various magazines, newspapers, and journals. Items in this collection are those that are less than 3 pages long; lengthier materials from the Sinclair library have been individually cataloged. "Gottesman" numbers refer to entries in Upton Sinclair: An Annotated Checklist, by Ronald Gottesman.
Related Material
See Sinclair mss., Sinclair mss. II, Sinclair mss. III, Sinclair mss. IV, Sinclair mss. V, Sinclair mss. VI, Sinclair mss. VII, also located at the Lilly Library, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana.
Acquisition Information
Purchase: 1957
Sinclair, Upton, 1878-1968
- The case of Jerome Davis. (In Unity. Chicago. v. 98, no. 11, Feb. 1, 1937. p. 217) Comment of Jerome Davis' latest book Capitalism and culture. Gottesman A1761., PS3537.I85 C385 (Box No Box)
- Desmond's "Democracy" / reviewed by Upton Sinclair. (In Reprint of the regular review of new books from The Chicago daily news. July 2, 1919) Gottesman A629[?]., PS3537.I85 D45 2 copies (Box No Box)
- If writers had a magic wand / Upton Sinclair. (In The Saturday review of literature. v. 30, no. 2, Jan. 11, 1947. p. 11–12: ill., ports.) Review of I wish I'd written that, ed. Eugene J. Woods. Gottesman A2047., PS3537.I85 I35 2 copies (Box No Box)
- Manassas / by Upton Sinclair. (In The independent: a weekly magazine. v. 57, no. 2920, Nov. 17, 1904. p. 1149–1150) Sinclair reviews his own book, Manassas, at the request of the editor., PS3537.I85 M251 (Box No Box)
- Pleasure and profit in self portrait of U.S. / by Upton Sinclair. (In The Los Angeles daily news. Dec. 2, 1950. p. 24, 27) Review of An anthology of American autobiography, ed. by Irving Stone. Gottesman A2081., PS3537.I85 P72 (Box No Box)
- "The profits of religion" / reviewed by Upton Sinclair. Chicago, 1919. 1 leaf; 27 x 30 cm. "Reprinted from the Wednesday Book Page of the Chicago Daily News, Wednesday, February 12, 1919." Gottesman A598., PS3537.I85 P987 2 copies (Box No Box)
- [Review of The prodigal parents, by Sinclair Lewis] (In Common sense. Mar. 1938. p. 22–23: ill.) Gottesman A1877., PS3537.I85 R46 (Box No Box)
- Since leaving home. (In Pearson's magazine. Jan. 1924. p. 55–56) A review of: Since leaving home / by Albert Wehde. Chicago: Tremonia Pub. Co., [1923] Gottesman A962., PS3537.I85 S392 (Box No Box)
- Socialism, red or white. (In The nation. v. 133, no. 3453, Sept. 9, 1931. p. 261–262) A review of Bolshevism at a deadlock, by Karl Kautsky. Gottesman A1343., PS3537.I85 S52 (Box No Box)
- Some new books / by Upton Sinclair. (From Wilshire's magazine. Feb. 1910. p. 16) Sinclair's opinions of Ann Veronica, by H. G. Wells; A certain rich man, by W. A. White; Toil of men, by I. Querido. Gottesman A365., PS3537.I85 S54 (Box No Box)
- "The story of a proletarian life": a review / by Upton Sinclair. (In The open forum. Los Angeles. v. 3, no. 27, July 3, 1926. p. 3) Review of a book by Bartolomeo Vanzetti. This number of The open forum also includes two letters by Sinclair: More letter to a capitalist; and, Government and business. Gottesman A1100., PS3537.I85 S76 (Box No Box)
- Two notable books / reviewed by Upton Sinclair. (In Wilshire's magazine. v. 14, no. 9, Sept. 1910. p. 15: port.) The books reviewed are: Twentieth Century socialism, by Edmond Kelly; and, Life of Karl Marx, by John Spargo. Gottesman A381 note., PS3537.I85 T957 (Box No Box)
- [Two notable books / reviewed by Upton Sinclair] (From The new age. Sept. 8, 1910. p. 444–445) The books reviewed are: Twentieth Century socialism, by Edmond Kelly; and, Life of Karl Marx, by John Spargo. Gottesman A381., PS3537.I85 T957 1910 (Box No Box)
- Über Emile Zola / von Upton Sinclair. (In Neues Österrreich. Vienna. Jänner 1954. p.12.) Book review. Gottesman A2145., PS3537.I85 U3 (Box No Box)
- Upton Sinclair's page. (In Appeal to reason. Girard, Kan. no. 1374, Apr. 1, 1922. p. 2) Contains the following articles by Sinclair: On being Charlie Chaplin; A story from Arden; Two unusual books. Gottesman A840., PS3537.I85 U948 (Box No Box)
- The voice is the voice of evil: from France comes this timely novel of men who adopted the devil's ways ... / by Upton Sinclair. (From the New York Times books review. Section 7. Mar. 18, 1951. p. 1, 20: port.) A review of The burned bramble, by Manes Sperber. New York, 1951. Gottesman A2087., PS3537.I85 V5 (Box No Box)
- What Columbus started: Richard Armour finds history hilarious. (In Pasadena star–news. May 17, 1953. p. 27: ill., port.) A review of Armour's It all started with Columbus. Gottesman A2128., PS3537.I85 W534 (Box No Box)